Right, fall in!
You are going on a nine day camp.
Get your ass in gear.
Run, run, move it, move it, move it!
You are now at the Kommandokorps.
The lesson I am going to give you today
is surely the most important lesson.
The enemy and the threat.
You cannot live in this country if
you don't know who the enemy is.
Who are the people threatening
our lives in this country?
And making things difficult for us?
Who threatens my life to the point
that my house has to look like a fort?
Who rapes a woman every 15 seconds
in South Africa?
Who has already murdered 2000 Afrikaners
Who are these animals?
And you must tell me.
Thank you, our Heavenly Father, that we know,
we are safe with you, Lord.
Father, we ask you to stay with us,
be with our Afrikaner leaders.
Be with us,
in our decisions and thoughts.
We ask for all of this with your blessing.
Amen.
"I am lost without the Blood of The Lamb"
Would you like to go on that camp?
Yes.
What all are we going to do on the camp?
Shooting training and that kind of thing?
It's an endurance camp.
We know Colonel Jooste's camps are tough.
Yes.
You mustn't make me come fetch you
if you can't handle it. You have to finish.
Once you start something, you have to see it through.
The army taught me.
If I wasn't in the army,
then I wouldn't have had discipline.
At the end of the day, if something goes wrong,
I am not going to run to anybody else.
I will solve that problem myself.
If I ask you, Deon, who you are,
you mustn't say to me you are a
Randfontiener or this or that.
You must say you are an Afrikaans son.
And you stand for your God, people and Fatherland.
And you have to be able to live it as well.
Was that high?
Yes, a bit high.
One down!
I bought the bow from a friend of mine.
Hannas was too small and weak to pull the string.
Eventually he got stronger as he grew up and got used to it.
Now he's trained to challenge the dlad.
But I'm winning!
Look on the scoreboard!
It's a Kommandokamp, in Afrikaans.
My dad told me about it.
My dad was in the army and everything.
So he told me I should go
to experience what he experienced,
to see how it is.
My basic training was ten weeks.
We're only going for nine days.
You're going for ten days, I went for ten weeks.
Take those army boots that I gave you.
Take them with you.
Boots that keep
Boots that are nice and strong.
You don't need to worry that much about bathing.
You're going to war.
Help your friends where you can.
Left. Left.
Left. Right. Left.
Squad! Halt. Stop. One, two.
Right, Colonel?
Look at the man in front,
look at the feet of the man in front of you.
When his feet touch the ground, so must yours.
Marker, move here. Like so.
Marker!
Move forward, I want the squad like this.
The bus needs to stand this way.
Get on the bus! Get on the bus!
Catch a wake up.
You're going to run if you don't work together!
Hey!
You must stand to attention.
Where's your chest?
Barnard!
Squad. Attention!
Three count right turn!
Right turn!
One, two, three.
One!
Right on the left flank.
Forward march!
These Commando Camps that we hold
are for the young boys,
to get some discipline in them,
to get some tidiness,
to learn order,
and also
a good military-style camp.
Dive roll!
I want to see your dick dragging in the dirt!
Move!
Please!
You are a new generation.
You are the Afrikaans generation.
We use a lot of mixed language,
lots of Afrikaans and English mixed together.
Good. We are going to try speak more Afrikaans.
Barnard, you look completely disorganised.
Barnard!
I'm here for the military to teach me
how to camouflage and that kind of thing.
The whole purpose of camouflage,
is to break form.
If you're on an operation in the bush,
what is the first thing you don't want to happen?
You don't want to get caught.
Or be seen. If you're seen,
make sure they can't identify you.
You must draw two lines on your face, like so and so.
No.
That will look like someone has drawn
a bullseye on your head.
Camouflage...
"Shocky" there at the back.
Sparky.
Make me a straight line from above the nose,
across his eyes and down the side.
Just use the mud.
The small boy, Deon.
Sparky. We call him Sparky.
Because he brought a Tazer in his bag.
And teargas. In his fucking bag!
We're on a camp!
Sparky the Clown.
We want to break form.
'Headboy" come here quickly.
I was chosen to be headboy by my fellow students.
It is a big responsibility and we form
the leadership of the children.
We basically walk around at school
to make sure everything is alright
and that nobody is doing something
they shouldn't be doing.
Cricket, tennis, revue, chess.
Public speaking, leadership.
Academics, Eisteddfod, revue, hockey.
Drama, chess, tennis, archery.
Shops Sport.
Pro Shops
Pro
Shops
Shops Archery.
Pro
Shops
Bass
Headboy.
To be headboy is a challenging position.
He's reached what I never reached.
Who of you ever thought you'd
be whistling that song for relaxation?
Never.
Your father sang that song every day
during the Border War.
This fat ass is just lazy!
I have to do everything for that fat boy!
He doesn't want to do anything for me.
Do you need a tampon, bro?
Why am I here?
Personal reasons.
I'm serious.
I screwed up.
Drugs. Cocaine.
11 years. Lots.
Every day.
Every bloody day.
I played for the Green Squad, the junior Springboks.
At school, yes.
That's where I've come from.
That's my past.
And I threw everything away.
Why? I was depressed.
So I just snorted.
Everything.
Just thrown away.
And I just want to prove again who that guy is,
who my mom and dad raised.
That's the important thing.
Definitely.
Self-defense.
Why do we need self-defense in this day and age?
For protection.
A lot of our women get raped, get assaulted.
Young boys your age have the same
amount of strength as a woman.
I'm not saying you're weak or anything.
Try to get yourselves this book.
You must study it. It's really good.
My mom has that book.
See if you can make copies for your friends.
It's illegal to make copies, but see what you can do.
What do you think are the statistics today?
How many woman are being raped as we speak?
This is why we want you guys
to be involved in the Kommando.
Our own people won't even help each other.
Guys, you need to step up.
So if you're walking in the city,
and these lizards start walking your way,
They're a group of three. What are they doing?
They take up the whole pavement.
Move out the way. Move out the way.
"You're an Afrikaner", and so on.
Do you know what I do when I'm walking in town?
And he's heading my way.
Listen, I'm going to hit you hard now, ok?
He's coming towards me.
Take him to the ground.
If he doesn't get out of my way,
I'll help him out of my way!
First of all, we are going to give you
a few lessons with a firearm.
We are going to show you a few tricks
to disarm someone.
Loaded or unloaded, you can do it.
All you have to do is move out, then move in...
There you go.
What we do is we give them training
to help protect themselves against attacks
especially farm attacks.
And also normal attacks during civil life.
In South Africa there are 60 people killed per day.
The first thing this lizard does is
stand with his gun like this.
He thinks he is Rambo through and through.
Now, what is a lizard?
The Sergeant used the word "lizard" as
a metaphor to describe the enemy.
He compares black people to a lizard.
When he stands with his firearm
like this, what is exposed?
Everything.
Everything is exposed.
All you do is kick him between the legs.
What will he do if you kick him between the legs?
He shoots over your head.
He falls to the ground, holding his weapon.
You should be long gone by then.
It's not our fault that 95% of the criminals
in this country are black.
It's not our fault that 99% of farm murders
are committed by black people.
It's obvious that people will begin to hate these creatures
that murder people regardless of their skin colour.
You can't blame it on just the black people.
There aren't just black people going around
murdering and stuff.
You get extremists in every race
and in every culture.
Crime will always be in every country.
I don't think it's the black people
making South Africa unsafe necessarily.
Poor people break in and steal stuff
because they need the money for something.
But yes, I don't know.
Small guys can also do it.
You. Come here.
You can also do it.
It's a quick movement.
You take it and you go.
He mustn't expect it.
Come on. Do it.
Do it quickly.
That's it.
-Hold tight.
Take it with force.
That's it!
That's it! Very good.
Today we got basic training in self-defense.
So if you're ever attacked in a home robbery
and someone holds a gun to your head
you know how to disarm him.
If they break into your home and
your dad's sleeping or your dad's out,
and they put a gun to your head,
you know what to do.
You never know what is going to happen.
You never know.
Come. Shove me.
All you do is grab his hands if
he comes at you again.
Move forward, pull him closer,
put your foot there,
and take him to ground.
Things like this happen in South Africa.
It happens across the country.
How can I explain it,
crime is everywhere.
I don't want to hurt you.
Give him hell!
What did you do wrong there?
I came over this way.
I'll show you a trick.
Grab my throat.
I'm small now. As small as you are.
What are you going to do?
Take your arm, bring it over and go down.
That's all you do. Drop down to your knees.
That's neat!
In 2005, they tried to steal R4000 from me, two..
criminals.
I actually shot and killed both of them.
Because I was trained.
Because I did this training.
Any person that tells you,
or a police officer that wants to arrest you
because you defended yourself,
just smack that officer on the ears because
he doesn't know the law.
You have the right to defend yourself
and to protect your own property.
In my opinion, if I was president of
this country, I'd say,
for every white person murdered in this country,
we must stand up and kill 40 of them.
That's my opinion.
It's not the WK's opinion, it's my opinion.
They're 40 against 1.
South Africa is bleeding.
And this is why we have to train our people.
To be prepared.
For any attack anywhere.
So all you do is you move forward the whole time.
Push! You move forward.
Move forward.
Uh uh. No.
Don't try and be clever now.
It's just speed that helps.
I'm not strong. Check out these skinny arms!
Sergeant, do it again. We didn't see!
- It's speed that counts.
No, no, no! Please!
My head.
Number one, what did you learn today?
How to take a gun from someone's hands.
Like from someone who's attacking you.
Do you think you'd be able to do it in the real world?
Yes.
Again!
Right on the left flank.
Right turn!
One, two, three.
One!
The lesson I am going to give you today is surely
the most important lesson,
the enemy and the threat
You cannot live in this country if
you don't know who your enemy is.
Who are the people who stand against us?
Who are the people threatening
our lives in this country?
Who are these animals?
And you must tell me.
Black people, Colonel.
You said it, not me.
There's a conflict between
white people and black people in this country.
We must accept this.
Why is there a conflict?
Number one.
There's an external conflict. We look different.
We don't look the same as each other.
They have thick lips.
The lips are likely to curl upwards.
Okay? We have thin lips.
You laugh, but it's the truth.
You see it every day.
The negroes ears on the inside
are totally different to ours.
It's much more sensitive.
That's why us Afrikaners know, hit them
against the ears and they'll fall to the ground.
Because their ears are made differently.
I don't know why we were being
taught about their noses.
If you have big ears,
does that make you someone else?
No.
Let's see what Dr. Carlton Putnam has to say.
Respected anthropologist. He says,
..clearly indicated that the negroes inferiority
to the white man,
average against average,
in many ways,
but in no way more significantly than in
the size and the weight of the brain,
especially in the measurements
of the brain's frontal cortex."
Your cortex is your forebrain.
Your forebrain is responsible for planning.
Your forebrain helps you take initiative.
Your forebrain helps you remember things,
to remember intsructions.
and to serve.
That's why there is not one country
in Africa that is a First-World Country.
Now we ask ourselves,
is there a difference in the intelligence levels
between a negro and a caucasian?
Dr Albert Schweitzer,
"One must look at the negro
not as one's equal, but as a child.
And with children,
nothing can be done without authority."
A black man has the intelligence level
of a 14-year-old white boy.
Dr Meredith Townsend says,
"Negroes have never advanced
out of the foulest savagery."
This is why they will kill you for nothing.
They have no moral values.
You need to know, who is the enemy?
Who will attack me?
How he looks.
It's not my fault he's black.
Colonel Jooste is a very clever man.
I didn't know he was that clever,
but he's terribly smart.
I don't believe something straight off the bat.
I'm very inquisitive, so I won't
accept anything he tells me right then and there.
I will do research to see if it is the truth.
This all information
that the press and international media
say you mustn't know.
They keep it away from you.
They smother it so that you don't know.
And the only place you'll hear it is here.
You won't hear it anywhere else.
You get black people that are extremist,
and you get white people that are extremist.
So on each side you have extremists,
the middle and the other extremists.
They are in conflict with each other,
and the middle group goes along like sheep.
I'm not an extremist, so I'm one of the sheep.
I find the new South Africa...
difficult.
There are difficult circumstances for us whites.
Especially to get work.
I, myself, am not chosen first for a position
that may be open at the mines,
because it's first the non-whites. Then his wife,
then his children. Then is it us.
We're last.
We eat off the ground, on our knees.
The Border War took place between 1966 and 1989.
And every young man had to go to the Border.
Most South African families had a brother,
a father or son on the Border.
So what now?
This!
This is the path that we must follow.
The training that you receive, the standard of
that training, is the same as what you just saw.
The path that we follow is the same
as the path that those men walked.
Nkosi sikelel' iafrika?
Don't go down that path.
What happened was, we went in,
we got orders to go in and go sweep.
Our first vehicle set off a land mine.
What happens when you set off a landmine is that
the doors fall open and you jump out.
And when we jumped out they were waiting for us.
Then they hit us.
When I hit they ground they shot me.
About three or four guys away,
my friend was shot through the head.
Dead.
Can you see it?
When we...
They shot me here.
Men.
You think we're all talk.
Now you've seen an example,
of what really happened,
to a man here with us.
This man's life at that stage,
was hanging on a thread finer than a hair.
This is why I lose my mind sometimes
when it comes to your training.
Because if we had not been trained,
or it had been you out there,
no one would have survived
You need to have discipline.
Discipline, discipline, discipline!
Because if you don't have discipline,
you can't execute an operation such as that.
If we're sitting around the camp fire one day,
no one can say,
you weren't in the army
and you didn't get this type of training,
I can say I've had this training...
but only for nine days, not for three months!
So yes. It's also something to be proud of,
if you can make it through.
Yes it's hard, but it makes you proud.
Everything we do, our dads did.
It was hard for them also and they always say..
we did it, we went to the army.
So this is kind of the same and now we've
done it so we can say we've done it as well.
Finishing this camp will make
me feel more like a man.
I can talk to my dad who was in the army
about what he's been through because
I've been through it as well..
in nine days.
My father?
My father is dead.
He was a big guy, and he drank a lot.
He got his life sorted out,
he gave his heart to the Lord.
He started coming right but it was too late
for him and my mom to try again.
But he did turn his life around,
so I can turn my life around as well,
and I can discipline my son in a
way he'll never forget,
if he ever even tries any of that shit.
That's the difference, I didn't have a dad.
I'm tired. We sleep three hours a day.
Sergeant Carstens smokes tobacco, ahum!
Those songs, I'm teaching them those.
Sergeant Carstens smokes tobacco
and sits on his ass the whole day, ahum!
Ahum! Ahum! Chicky bum, chicky bubblegum!
I have to fucking teach it to them
because we have nothing fun to do here.
and they ask me all the time for a bunch of shit.
But it's also actually to help
keep their minds off the KFC,
and the damn Steers burgers and
whatever the hell else they're craving.
We find him at the Magistrate. ahum!
We find him at the Magistrate, ahum!
We find him at the Magistrate, the Magistrate
he pulls my leg, ahum!
Barnard is small.
He's really small so we don't really listen to what he says.
He sometimes says silly things.
Stupid things.
The Colonel's coming!
He tries to fit in.
But he'll fit in if he stops trying so hard.
He just needs to relax and be himself
because I don't think this is him.
I've made friends.
But everyone's so tired so,
they get a bit angry sometimes.
Work together!
Come on, stay strong!
Don't fucking pull me back, push me!
I'm doing that! Your back isn't straight!
It's very difficult.
I'm not very good, you see,
and everyone makes mistakes in life
and you start when you're young,
up until you become a Colonel then
you can perfect everything.
Help your smaller friends.
Somebody swap with him.
Come here Barnard. Go there
I like it here.
All your friends are around you,
they tell you stories about their dads in the army,
and when they do that we think about our parents
and then I think, wow,
I could be just like my dad one day.
Deon is more of a bush person.
Friends can bring lots of problems.
We also don't have any friends and stuff.
Because we believe that too many friends
and material possessions
can bring problems. We don't do that.
It's all about our family,
and the time God has granted us with our family.
That's how we raise them.
At night he is not out on the streets and
we brought up our daughters the same way.
You'll see, Deon isn't interested in watching rugby.
We don't watch any rugby,
you'll see we don't even have TV's.
We believe that sport has become the
god in this country.
We don't want anything to do with that.
Deon has a TV in his room where he watches DVDs,
but only DVDs that we've approved.
Put in a little water.
Our family isn't on BBM or Facebook
or anything of that sort.
We're not looking for sinful things.
Those are sinful.
Yes, they still give me hidings.
If I do something wrong
And it is painful, but you have to learn.
Like, look at the white kids of today.
The new generation. The new age.
The wear tongue rings, they drink, they smoke.
They use drugs and have tattoos.
I don't want to be like that one day.
I want to keep my body clean.
I won't drink. I won't smoke.
I won't get any tattoos. I won't use drugs.
It looks good.
Maybe a bit too much oil.
Deon doesn't play TV games and things like that.
We say he must rather do other things, like,
Deon can shoot very well. More things for himself.
- More practical things.
More practical things that will develop him.
Otherwise he only develops his head.
And he'll walk around like a kid
with a swollen head.
This is the longest period
in five years.
...five years that I've been
away from my wife and kids
The most had been three days
when I went to write my trade exams.
...to get my qualification.
Three days.
It is hectic.
It's shit!
We met when my oldest son was one year old.
He's turning seven in November.
We were engaged for a year.
And we've been married for five years.
There's nobody else for me.
There's only her
Believe me, I can't
seemyself...
with anyone else besides her.
She
- I don't think he suits anyone else,
I think he'll drive them crazy.
Yes!
I really don't think anyone else can tolerate him.
No, I couldn't live without her
She is my everything.
We first met through a girlfriend of hers.
I'd just started using, I was using for about
seven months then.
When she was pregnant we didn't use.
and then she started again too.
I'm now... what's today? Sunday?
I'm two weeks clean today.
No, I'll overcome.
I have to. I have no other choice.
It's for my children.
These guys don't know..
what could happen or...
They all happy, thinking it's all about paintball.
They all have their parents.
My father was in the army.
He wore this uniform that I am wearing today.
He also fought in the Border War.
He told me lots of stories, so yes,
I am very close to my dad.
I'm cleaning these boots for him.
It's an order he gave me.
All of these boots have a history.
They came from S.A. Army Supply Stores,
and guys like us who donated them.
But all of them were in the army. All these boots.
If the boots could speak,
you'd hear stories you wouldn't believe.
If we do not do it, we're going to get shit.
He's the one making...
making shit for us so that we have to run.
Where's my bush hat?
Who's got my bush hat?
Where is the Colonel's bush hat?
I gave it back to you, Colonel.
No! My bush hat!
If you've lost that hat I'll kill you.
You're all going to shit yourselves!
There it is. You said you gave it back to me.
- It was with you the whole time.
- Sorry, Colonel.
This is the wrong hat.
You're going to run all day if that hat is gone.
Right, for the next 15 minutes
you're going to look for that hat.
Come. You're going to look for
that bush hat until you find it.
Look under cars. On the ground. But find it.
Yes, we found the hat.
They gave it to me because they were arguing about it.
"Take the hat!", "No! I don't want to see
the Corporal! You take the hat.", "No!"
So I said, "Give me the fucking hat!"
And then I went and gave him the hat.
I went to him and said, "Here's your hat."
I thought everything was okay.
But he said, "No, now you're in shit. I'm done."
You can thank your lucky stars!
Where did you find the hat?
It was with me the whole time, Colonel.
This one?
That I had before?
- Yes, Colonel.
Don't talk shit.
Apologise to the Colonel for his bush hat.
Sorry, Colonel.
I can't hear you!
Sorry, Colonel!
I don't like it when people
do what they're not supposed to do.
Or if they do it wrong.
because you have to tell them so many times
"You do it like this."
No, they won't do it like that.
So we must suffer.
We showed him!
From now on, you will all run for the rest of the camp.
You heard me! Move! Run!
For the next person who walks instead
of runs to where they need to be,
the consequence will be that everyone will do
corrective training for the rest of the day.
Am I understood?
Yes, Sergeant.
I can't hear you!
Yes, Sergeant!
I. Can't. Hear. You!
Make a line over there.
Run, guys!
First person!
Run!
Do a dive roll into the mud,
then leopard crawl to the other side.
Hey Sparky! What the fuck are you doing?
The leopard crawl or playing in the mud?
Dive roll!
I want to see your dick dragging in the dirt!
Not just your arms, use your legs as well.
Move!
Yes, I'm not just going to give up.
I will persevere.
I will test myself. I will test my body
to the limit that I can withstand.
Go help your friends!
- I can. I will. I want to.
You have to work together as one man!
I'm alright, I'm alright, I can do it on my own.
- I can, I will, I want to!
- No! We can help you!
I can, I will, I want to!
I will perservere and make it through.
People who perservere win.
There you go!
You made it.
You made it. Well done.
Thank you, Sergeant.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Stand still.
Go clean yourself up at the water tower.
You don't have to do anything else until after lunch.
Yes, Sergeant.
Will you make it?
Yes I will make it.
Ok, just don't fall over on the way there.
I won't.
That guy works alone.
He doesn't ask anyone to help him.
If he stays focused, he'll make it through.
I firmly believe he can do it.
What's wrong, Sparky?
- My arm.
- What's wrong?
It's burning and throbbing. It's sore.
Okay, I'll go speak to the Sergeant.
No, it's alright.
Damn it.
Training is hard on all of us, especially
because we can't do most of the stuff.
It's extreme.
Sergeant, can I wash out my eyes?
Why?
I can't see, the mud splashed into my eyes.
Do you think a terrorist with a bazooka will say
"Go wash your eyes out so you can see me."?
- No Sergeant.
- So that you can shoot him first?
Then fall in and do your job!
Three!
Big boy.
- Yes, Sergeant?
I'm already angry.
Do you want to make me furious?
Big Boy, keep going.
Come on, Big Boy!
One!
Two!
Big Boy.
Roll all the way to that side.
Just you. Roll to the other side.
You're making me angry.
They're falling apart a bit.
Big Boy is struggling.
With him... he needs a little support.
That's the main thing, because, he doesn't have that.
support.
The important thing now is that we all help each other.
If a guy falls, pick him up.
Walk slower! We aren't leaving him!
Can everyone hear me?
Yes!
Everyone! Has everyone heard me?
We're not leaving him!
Come, Big Boy!
Give him space!
Shift up!
Come, Big Boy!
Make space!
You and I are together.
Come here. Together with me.
All together now!
Come, Big Boy!
You've got it!
You have it! Push it!
I want to. I will. I can.
Move!
You've got this. Come!
I can't, buddy.
Come let's try.
Come, let's just go five metres
Four metres!
Come, let's just go two metres.
Come!
There you go.
That's it! With me.
With me!
Push him! Push him! Push him!
Is your friend working along? Come and help him.
Come back. Hurry up!
That's fucking good, man.
Come, Shaun!
I don't want to quit because it's going to
make me look like a little baby.
I don't want to look like a baby, we're at an army camp!
Not a little sissy camp.
Shaun is in front of us! Come, Shaun!
Go, Shaun!
Shaun's in front of us!
Shaun's in front of us! Come on!
...18, 19, 20.
Good!
Put your hands above your head.
Open up your lungs.
Well done, we are proud of you.
Well done, Shaun.
These are the parents of the Rossouw boys.
I'm here to pick up my two sons because
we're going on holiday.
Yes, that's that.
I missed you guys.
Didn't you miss me?
How's it going?
Apparently I have to go and ask for permission,
so maybe he'll let you go,
maybe he won't.
So keep doing everything you are supposed to do
and I'll go and talk to the big boss.
Then we'll talk again.
I'll see you just now.
Of course I want to
go home with my parents.
I dont think we'll be allowed to though..
because it's him.
Tell me, how did you get here?
How did you know where we were?
Someone in town told me
approximately were you are.
And on the way here
there were blacks on the road.
And I asked them, "Where are the soldiers?"
One of the boys got in the
car with me and brought me here
He showed me where it was.
They're going to get corrective training now.
Who's that now?
All the boys.
Is it?
Yes, because parents came here and
they aren't allowed on a military base.
No, no, no! I had to come fetch
my boys, we're going on holiday.
Oh.
I wasn't told about it and you should have
cleared it with me first. I'm in charge here.
Oh, ok.
You haven't had military training?
No, I guess thats why I don't know...
Civilians are not allowed on a military base.
That's just how it is.
But this is an opportunity to make sure they know.
No, of course. I understand.
You can watch, but they'll have to do
some pole running for old time's sake.
No, thats 100%.
We won't kill them.
Some of the boys mommies
and daddies came to visit the camp.
Is that permitted?
Are civilians permitted on a military base?
Hey? Answer me!
No, Colonel.
So we'll have to have one last run with our lovers, hey?
The hardest part was the running and jogging.
with the poles.
With your wife, they call it 'Lover'.
So that is your weapon, you can't drop her.
Move!
Hit the ground!
Leopard crawl!
Drop your asses!
You look like a bushman maid
with your ass in the air!
Move! Move! Move!
Colonel Jooste says that when
your body is exhausted
you can still run 60km before you die.
So I keep that in mind.
And I tell myself I haven't done 60km yet
so I can still carry on.
Stand up!
Stand up! The whistle blew!
Wait for Sparky!
Come, Sparky! Come!
Move that ass!
Don't let her touch the ground.
You don't lie on your lover!
Do you do that with all the women?
Keep your lover above your head!
Wait for Sparky!
Come, Sparky! Push yourself!
Move! Move! Move!
Put it down. The Colonel wants to speak to you.
You need discipline to break away from home,
to break away from mommy and daddy.
But Rossouw brings his mommy and daddy here
Hey, Rossouw? Where are you?
Both of you!
Did you bring your mommy and daddy here?
Not? Did they come here on their own?
The purpose of this camp is to make a man out of you.
We don't want mommy and daddy here, ok?
Do you understand me?
Yes, Colonel!
Remember, they need to let go of their mother's apron string
No, of course.
They need to let go.
They need to learn to be on their own.
My boys will have to come back
and do another camp.
My two "farm boys", I can't do anything.
You must get your stuff and go with your parents.
It's not my choice
it's your parents' choice.
There's the road.
See you, my friend.
When I came down here and asked the blacks,
"Where is the army?"
And they said,
"No, you want the soldiers?"
I said, "Yes I want the soldiers
- Yes, they know where.
I paid him R100 and said,
"Come with me, so I know exactly where to go.
- So he came with me, but only up to a point.
- Yes, they won't come any closer. They know.
We get funny things here at night. Infrared lights.
Security patrols. Then they leave again.
The government is watching us.
Yes, of course.
Come. Come. Come.
Come on farm boys, hurry up!
It's getting late! It's getting late! It's getting late!
They say that all the generations
after 1994 were born free.
I was born in 1995.
So in 2013 I'll be turning 18.
I think everybody is equal now.
I think it's the way it's supposed to be.
Everybody has equal rights to vote.
It's democratic.
They want you to believe that you're
part of the Rainbow Nation.
So they give you a flag that means different things.
And they give you a song where you sing
a little bit of Afrikaans, Xhosa and English.
A mixture of things.
How can we be proud of such a thing?
They've been indoctrinating our children since 1994,
with TV advertisements and programmes telling them
about the new, so-called Rainbow Nation.
And they can't have been very succesful
if we change that in nine days time.
Then they are not very succesful.
Everytime we have one of these camps,
we change it in nine days time.
And then these kids see that they belong to a
different nation, they belong to a very proud nation.
They will say, but we will show you,
you white people, you can do nothing if we
change your names,
if we change your flag, if we change
your national anthem,
you can do nothing about it,
but through this camp, we will show them.
Not just here though, but we will keep your names.
We are going to move forward with you,
and 1000 other boys will do this training too.
We will show them, and we will fight
against what they're doing to us.
One of the biggest goals of the camp is to
bring back patriotism into our boys:
to teach them that they are not a part
of this artificially created Rainbow Nation,
which has been pushed down their throats
since 1994,
The children of our children won't have any idea
of where they come from.
How can you move forward if you
don't know who you are?
And that's what we are fighting for.
What does the green stripe of the flag mean?
The Western faith and the Africa... Afrikaner
come together and head towards the future together.
The Western faith and the African faith come together
at one point and go into the future as one combined faith.
Colonel Jooste showed us both flags,
Winnie Mandela's g-string, that's the current national flag.
And then we have our...
orange, white, blue.
He told us to choose the new flag
or the orange, white and blue.
I think I will choose the orange, white, blue.
It's much prettier, and it is..
our Afrikaner blood's pride.
I chose the current national flag.
But I have an orange, white and blue flag
in my room.
attended the camp for the first time
when I was 16.
It was a training camp in Naboomspruit.
One of my best friends invited me to the camp.
In 2010 I started coming to the camps again.
In the summer we did the basics camp again,
and by the December camp
we started assisting as instructors.
And we are still helping out as instructors,
whilst we are busy with our officers courses.
Can you identify him?
Yes.
You can see exactly who he is.
It's not going to work.
I've always wanted to go to the army,
but our local army's standards are extremely low.
And I want something that is with my people.
We have a history to be proud of.
Don't be ashamed of your history.
We had everything taken by them.
You must wake up.
They stole almost everything from us.
And you'll also learn that we are a nation
that has a right to have their own land.
If the Swazi's have their own country
less than 500km away,
the Swazi's have Swaziland.
Then why can't the Afrikaners have Afrikanerland?
For us there is only one way..
to get independence, to fight for our freedom.
For our own Fatherland.
I'm now going to divide you into two groups.
One must hide away, and the other must patrol.
We're going to drop you into the deep end,
straight into the shit!
Okay, go hide.
The guys like this.
They really like this.
They're going to shoot him
now now.
You know why?
Where are the rest of his guys?
He flanked them into the bush,
and he's got no control over them.
They're out of sight.
They're out of sight, they're out of...
You're dead, you bastard.
Oh my fuck.
Right, let's stand up.
Because my patrol made a fuck up.
Hello!
Just one question.
How willing are you to fight for your freedom?
Completely.
Everyday. Everything it takes of me.
I got his feeling three weeks ago that my dad..
when I went so crazy,
and used cocaine,
I got the feeling... that he was watching me..
from above... and it's..
He wouldn't be happy.
But, maybe now it'll be a bit better.
So yes, I... have to get this right.
I think he'd be proud of me for coming here.
Get your team, you need to patrol the perimeter,
and you need to hurry up.
Remember, you're sleeping out there tonight!
You won't get your cover pitched in time.
You'll sleep in the wet and cold!
We are going to have to build our own temporary base.
So we're going into the bush to build it.
It's too wet.
It's too wet to put the sail up, we must sleep
on the sail, otherwise we aren't going to get any sleep.
It's really a load of shit.
This.
You guys, come lie in the bush.
So we can come and shoot you. Fucked up.
And you can't sleep... Again!
We must be wide awake. Understand?
There is a lot of nice space
so that we can runaway if they come.
- Small boy?
- Yeah?
Small boy, you stay with me.
Hear me?
You fucking stay with me here.
Don't show that, they'll know we're here.
If you want to buy out a town.
Go to the farmers, they can all put their farms together.
But their farms will still remain as their farms.
Yes, they will!
And move the town's borders.
- That's what I'm saying... you don't buy it from them.
- It doesn't have to be...
It stays 100% theirs.
But they set it up as a new border point for our country.
All I'm saying is use the outside.
Use their stupidity.
And strengthen yourself.
Use them from the outside.
Like a farmer, if he wants to be included,
as a border for us,
let him sell his corn to the outside.
Here is his border.
There is his house and his stuff.
He comes in, he comes to work,
six o' clock, he goes.
- And the same goes for us?
Yes.
If he has to leave my area at six,
I have to leave his area at six.
Yes, that's all we need to do.
Use them, as long as we need them.
They're not going to think they're
being mistreated. No.
They just see that life goes on.
They see the money coming in,
because you have to pay them.
Here comes the money. The money's coming.
So what. Okay. Yes, money comes. That's it.
Who shot at us?
Headboy, you bastard!
Turn around.
Turn. Go back.
I only want to do this once to get the experience
and to see how the training is.
I don't want to be an active..
participant in the Kommandokorps.
I just want to do the training to get the experience.
We could see you from a mile away.
We first heard you from way over on the other side
and you led us straight to the base.
You know this is a simulation of a real exercise.
What would have happened if this was real?
Once again the lookout fell asleep on duty,
because your friends' lives obviously weren't
important enough to stay awake for.
You all need to stand in a row for two shots
before you pack up.
Just because you got caught.
You've had your shots.
I'm starting the stop watch.
You have eight minutes to get
all the gear back to base camp.
Move!
As a son of the AWB, I begin at camps like these.
The AWB stands for
the Afrikaner Resistance Movement,
and here, as you can see, the three sevens,
are not really like Hitler's Swastika, as people say.
They're the three sevens that oppose
the 666 of the Anti-Christ in the Bible.
The Beast.
So the three sevens is the perfect number,
of our God and his glory.
God, our people and Fatherland.
That's what it stands for.
It's not racist, nor is it about racism.
It's about who you are, what you are
and what you stand for.
We believe that this is part of a bigger plan
to the eliminate an entire nation.
This is why we give them the training.
We don't give them attack training but rather
discipline and self defense training.
We must learn how to bring our people together again.
On certain dates you can see,
if you put certain dates together,
you can see exactly when a war will erupt.
We are now in that phase - where we are
waitingfor them to attack us.
And believe me, we're waiting for them to attack first.
And that day... they'll run.
They're going to run into the sea.
Because we're going to turn around
and start shooting back.
This is one of our anthems.
On a mountain in the night
we lie in darkness and wait.
I lie cold in the mud and blood,
my bag and the rain cling to me.
My Bible says I mustn't mix with them.
According to my country's history and the like,
look at what happened at Blood River.
Piet Retief and his men wanted to negotiate,
and they murdered him.
And I can no longer allow our people to be wiped out.
The day that WVK tell me,
"we're picking up our weapons"
I will pick up my weapon and go with my people.
De La Rey, De la Rey
Will you lead the Afrikaners?
General, General.
We will follow you as one man.
General De La Rey.
If we don't get our land,
if they don't want to accept that
we are an independent nation
and we strive for our freedom, then it's a freedom
struggle, we will start a freedom struggle.
like all the other nations in this world.
We have the ability.
We have the men.
We just need to plant the will in you,
because you've been brainwashed
by old Mandela and all that stuff.
Be proud of your people, be proud of your race.
Be proud of your faith, be proud of your culture.
You have the right to be proud.
I'm not forcing this down your throat
because you came here willingly
That makes you better than us.
Why does it make you better than us?
Because it was compulsory for you.
We had to. We were called up with conscription papers.
We were forced to do it.
We were forced by the government.
Most of those guys wouldn't
have been there if they weren't ordered.
You've come voluntarily.
Well, not entirely voluntarily, because you
thought it was all about paintball, didn't you?
So we needed to camouflage it a bit for you.
But you've heard what I've said now,
we don't want to make war.
Nobody wants to make war.
It's not a nice thing to make war.
But if you have to do it..
don't see that person as a person..
see him as a mark that you have to eliminate.
Eliminate the mark and put it behind you.
And don't let it screw with your head.
Otherwise you'll go crazy.
I would like to be a member of the
Kommandokorps as a Sergeant or something
National salute!
Ringing out from our blue heavens.
From our deep seas breaking round.
Over everlasting mountains.
Where the echoing crags resound.
In the Bible it says black people must live with black
people and white people must live with white people.
You cannot mix nations.
I don't have black friends.
If they can stay on their side, I can stay on mine.
Then there's no problem.
If they come to my side and
ask to speak to me, I will say no.
Or I will turn my back on them and walk away.
The AWB is just like the Kommandokorps.
There are lots of right-wing groups.
It's more about self-defense.
If they say the black people are
attacking white people,
the AWB will come in,
and they will say, "You need to leave,
or we will shoot you."
Then the black people will hit the road,
and all the other races.
Stay behind the camera guys.
Don't record them, ok?
Ok.
You, come here.
We Afrikaners want our freedom.
We want our own country
We will continue to burn
this flag until the day we get our freedom.
No one will force us to stand under this flag.
We Afrikaners want our freedom.
We want our own country.
We want our own country
We Afrikaners want our freedom.
We want our own country.
Burn, bastard, burn.
As we long as we Afrikaners are ruled by a
communist regime, we will burn that thing.
It's not our flag and no communist will rule us.
If they burn it they burn it, I can't stop it.
But they will..
they will carry the consequences.
I was singing because it made me feel pr. not proud,
but it made me feel like part of the group.
I didn't want to just stand there and
keep my mouth shut.
I wouldn't burn the flag myself.
To put it that way.
I liked it when I saw the flag burn.
That fucking shit flag.
Because I don't like it.
Remember I'm not as young as these guys.
I know about our old flag. I know about 1994.
I know what my father lost.
For me it's plainly and simply - a shit flag.
It doesn't bother me at all.
Burn the damn thing.
If we're called up to stand together as one
to get our own nation, to get our own country,
I will stand with them.
I believe all the men here will also stand together.
Our people will stand together as one.
To get our own freedom.
My mind has changed a lot about black people.
The negativity has grown.
Colonel Frans has opened our eyes to all
the bad things that black people do.
They won't change.
I didn't...
participate in the burning of the flag completely,
because I don't want to disgrace that flag,
because one day when I'm in the airforce, I'm going
to fight for that flag and I want to be proud of it.
Look here, everyone's got their opinions.
I don't like these black people. That's the truth.
You can tell everyone in the whole world.
I don't like black people.
The truth about this whole thing and why I'm here is
for me to get training, if the black nation attacks us.
If that nation attacks, I'll know what to do.
It is a guarantee.
There will be a war in this country.